Tyler Brown

Miami, FL 33130

Phone: 551-208-8486 | Email: tyler.brown7837@gmail.com

LinkedIn: http://linkedin.com/in/tyler-brown-002b4919b | GitHub: https://github.com/Starcode897

Summary

Driven by a newfound passion for data science. Capable of molding large quantities of data into simple and comprehensive visualizations, palatable to any and all interested parties. Made use of multiple Python libraries to solve problems encountered in multiple projects.

Technical Skills

Tools: Python, JavaScript, HTML, SQLAlchemy, Pymongo, R, Matplotlib, Leaflet, Plotly, Pandas, VBA, Tableau, Scikit-learn

Additional Tools: Predictive Analytics, Machine Learning

Databases: SQL, MongoDB

Projects

Aviation Incident Visualizations | https://github.com/rar254/project-2

- Summary: Built a website that visualizes aviation incident data over a 76 year period.
- Role: Scraped aviation incident database for information and used said information to construct a visualization. Used a flask application to link html pages.
- Languages: JavaScript, Python, HTML

Food Desert Analysis | https://github.com/Ssimoes48/Food-Deserts-Analysis

- Summary: Determined whether the presence of a food desert deserves more or less attention from a planning perspective.
- Role: Utilized for loops to iterate through project data and create graphs for statistical analysis.
- Languages: Python

Telecom Pricing Prediction | https://calm-headland-26707.herokuapp.com/

- **Summary**: Built a machine learning model that predicts an optimal telecom price.
- Role: Used flask application to link HTML pages and assisted with model construction.
- Languages: Python, HTML

Experience

Remote Cartographer Volunteer United States Geological Survey National Map Corp

2021 - Present

Miami, FL

- Edited existing map structures on USGS virtual map.
- Added structures to the USGS virtual map based on existing locations.

Cashier2018 - 2018The Home DepotSecaucus, NJ

- Used Home Depot's risk mitigation strategies to reduce loss.
 - Processed customer sales with fast, friendly and accurate service at point of purchase.
 - Solved customer problems by providing directions and insights into products.
 - Recognized by the manager for being a capable employee. Trusted to operate the register, one week before the end of training period.
 - Maintained perfect attendance and volunteered to extend shift to assist with closing responsibilities.

Food Bank Volunteer

Garden State Episcopal Church

2013 - 2015

Jersey City, NJ

- Unloaded groceries from delivery trucks into the warehouse.
- Ensured grocery bags included all items necessary for weekly distribution.
- Identified customers in need of assistance and found ways to improve their experience.

Volunteer Donor Coordinator

The American Red Cross

2013 - 2015

Jersey City, NJ

- Welcomed donors upon arrival and provided preliminary information as needed.
- Maintained appointment schedules and notified staff of scheduling conflicts or delays.
- Identified signs of illness or reaction and alerted medical professionals in event of client deterioration.
- Encouraged donors to enjoy snacks to avoid dehydration.

Education

Spring 2021 Data Science and Visualization Boot Camp Certificate: Rutgers University Newark NJ [6 month program] Spring 2020 Bachelor's Degree: Rutgers University Geoscience (Minor in Environmental Science) Newark NJ